♪ 我的站到了 ♪
♪ This is my stop ♪
♪ 得下车了 ♪
♪ Got to get off ♪
♪ 还敢更挤嘛 ♪
♪ I might go pop ♪
借过
Excuse me
♪ 原谅我这么直 ♪
♪ I've got to be direct ♪
♪ 如冒犯请指教 ♪
♪ If I'm off, please correct ♪
♪ 你挡着我道了 ♪
♪ You're standing on my neck ♪
拽妹Daria
漫迪字幕组倾情奉献
——·旗木译制·——
嘿 丫头
Hey, kiddo!
猜你是在琢磨老爸的大炖锅里在做什么美味吧
Guess you're wondering what old Dad is up to with the big stew pot.
再猜
Guess again.
Daria 老爸大半夜被一个想法给弄醒了
Daria, I woke up in the middle of the night with a hankering.
来给厨师送吻吧
我忽然就想起来以前军校...
I suddenly remembered the old kitchen sink stew
他们总给我们做的槽炖大菜了
they used to serve us at the military academy!
知道为啥叫槽炖大菜不?
You know why they called it that?
论道德科幻
因为他们把食材全都扔到厨房水槽里炖
Because they put in everything but the kitchen sink.
Because they put in everything but the kitchen sink!
看看哈 老汤 干胡椒 牛至叶 干辣椒
Hmm, let's see... soup stock, peppercorns, oregano, chilies...
你爸这是怎...
Why is your father...?
别问我
Don't ask.
看东西呢是吧?
Reading something?
嗯
Yes.
能问问是啥不?
May I ask what it is?
书 老师的任务
It's a book. For school.
讲科幻小说存在的意义远远不止娱乐大众
About how fiction should do more than just entertain.
听起来蛮有趣的
That sounds interesting.
是啊 一个作家出书阐述作家应该如何写书
Yeah. A writer writing a book about how writers should write books.
肯定会是一本畅销书
Must have been a huge seller.
那... 学校里有没有发生别的什么事?
Well... anything else going on in school?
我想想 这礼拜没人跟我搭话
Let's see... nobody talked to me again this week,
周末也没被邀请参加任何派对
I wasn't invited to any parties for the weekend,
另外我嘴边好像长了几颗巨疼无比的疱疹
and I think I'm getting one of those really painful cold sores.
所以总结一下 又是超赞的一周
So all in all, another great week.
Daria啊
Oh, Daria...
Helen Helen 911电话号码是多少来着?!
Helen! Helen! What's the number for 911?!
Daria 你看事情一定要这么消极的眼光吗?
Daria, do you have to look at everything in such a negative light?
那您意思是让我用自然界的刺眼日光吗?
Could you possibly be referring to the harsh light of reality?
Tiffany说会有一股冷锋来袭
Tiffany says a cold front is coming through.
你们谁看见我那件超萌的粉红绒绒毛衣了吗?
Has anyone seen my really cute fuzzy pink sweater?
我找不到了 可不可以再买一件 谢啦
And if I can't find it can I buy another one? Thanks.
- Daria - 别劳神了
- Daria... - Don't bother.
我的舌头 老天啊 都发黑了 Helen呐
My tongue! Dear God, it's black! Helen!
这就来啦 Jake
Be right there, Jake.
因此加德纳想要告诉我们的是 科幻小说的作者...
So, what Gardner is telling us is that the writer of fiction
应当不仅仅把职责限于给读者讲述一个故事
has a duty that goes beyond the mere telling of a story.
他们的职责应该是 在讲故事的同时 让读者们能够...
His or her job is to tell a story in such a way as to leave the reader...
怎样呢 Kevin?
what, Kevin?
呼唤更多的激烈肉搏场景?
Screaming for more full-contact martial arts excitement?
Daria?
我想加德纳先生是希望作者能够...
I believe Mr. Gardner feels it's the writer's duty
引导读者能够更加向善而为
to steer the reader toward more conscientious behavior.
不管这会使故事变得多么无趣
No matter how dull that makes the story.
非常好 Daria
Very good, Daria.
好了 把这件事牢记于心 我希望大家每人...
Now, keeping that in mind, I want you each
选择从面前的书单中选择一本书 就其道德导向写一篇报告
to select a book from the list in front of you for a report on its moral intention.
怎么了 Kevin?
Yes, Kevin?
住在玻璃房里的人不应该乱扔石头
People who live in glass houses shouldn't throw stones.
我抢到一个 宝贝 抢到一个
I got one, babe. I got one!
打扰下
Excuse me.
怎么了 Daria
Yes, Daria?
您给的书单... 我已经全读完了
This list of books... I've read all of them.
这样啊
Oh, no.
那你想不想再多读一本呢?
Um, would you like to pick another book to read then?
- 可以吧 - 等等 脑暴时间
- I guess. - Wait, brainstorm!
与其再读一个以道德引导为目的的故事
Instead of trying to read a story for its moral dimensions,
你何不亲自尝试写一个这样的故事?
what if you wrote a story with moral dimensions?
独家课业任务 只派给你哦
A special assignment, Daria just for you.
我不知道 写什么人好呢?
I don't know. Who would I write about?
写他们什么呢?
What would they do?
这个... 不如你把在现实生活中认识的人集结到故事中
Well, why don't you write a story taking people you know in real life
再把他们转换成虚构角色
and turning them into fictional characters?
我在想会有人看出差别吗?
I wonder if anyone would notice the difference.
你那故事构思怎样了?
So, how's the story coming?
我说话不会打扰到你吧?
Or does it disturb you if I talk while you're writing?
我要是真有动笔 你才会打扰到我
It would disturb me if I were actually doing any writing.
这有何难?
What's the problem?
把你认识的人写进去 随心所欲安排他们做的事
Take people you know and have them do whatever you want.
要是我 就让他们满地匍匐 匍匐
I'd make them crawl, I tell you. Crawl!
放松 虎妞
Easy, tiger.
你到底要写谁?
Who you going to write about?
没思路啊
I haven't a clue.
写Kevin和Brittany怎么样?
How about Kevin and Brittany?
你可以从他们的激萌恋爱一路写到浪漫童话婚礼
You could write a thrilling romance leading up to their storybook wedding.
再激萌浪漫 也得先有个开始才行啊
You need to start wearing a hat when you go out in the sun.
我去 要不我在这俩货过不下去要上吊时掺和一脚?
Boy, would I like to be there when those two tie the noose.
那么你 Kevin
And do you, Kevin,
是否愿意娶这位美貌的女子做你的合法妻子?
take this pulchritudinous woman to be your lawfully wedded wife?
Kevin
Kevin!
我... 您说啥?
I, uh... what did you say?
我说 你 Kevin 是否愿意承担法律责任
I said, do you, Kevin, assume legal responsibility
娶你身旁这位成熟大发的怪女人为妻?
for this overripe specimen of femalehood standing next to you?
穿白衣服这位 孩子
The one in white, son!
Kevin Kevin
Kevin! Kevin!
说啊
Well?!
回答人家呀 Kevvy
Answer him, Kevvy!
Kevin
Kevin!
Jane
Jane!
Brittany
Ah... Brittany.
请接受我对你不幸遭遇的深切慰问
Please accept my condolences on the unfortunate way,
在你人生最重要的日子里 他跑了
the biggest day of your life, has turned out.
爽
Yes!
Daria? Daria 写写他们的婚礼嘛
Daria? Daria! What about their wedding?
想想就觉得会很有意思
Wouldn't that be funny to write about?
什么? 算了... 我不觉得
What? Uh... no. I don't know.
好吧...
Okay...
我意思是... 要是写结成配偶仪式的题材
I mean, if I were going to write about mating rituals,
那我还不如写几百年前的那种
I think I'd go back a couple hundred years,
那时候女人要么选择结婚 要么就孤独终老
when women either married or shriveled up and blew away.
而不是像现在这样结完婚以后孤独终老对吧?
Instead of marrying and then shriveling up, like they do now?
Lane先生昨天把卡片都落下了
Mr. Lane left his card yesterday.
妈妈说每次来拜访你 他就特别特别紧张
Mother said he appeared most anxious to call upon you.
真想不通是为什么 Lane先生的脾气 看法...
I cannot imagine what for. Mr. Lane's temperament, outlook,
气质和他怪异的风度更容易让人产生困惑
indeed, his very manners are such as to arouse bemusement
胜过了对他的热心所生发出的喜爱
rather than endearment in the object of his attentions.
他太古怪
He's flaky.
虽然确实有些古怪 可终有一天 整个德文天郡都会是他的
Flaky though he may be, one day, all of Devonheavenshire will be his...
真不知道到时谁能那么幸运成为Lane太太呢
his to share with whosoever is lucky enough to become Lady Lane.
乖妹妹呀 我真心希望不管谁成为Lane太太
Dear sister, I would hope that whoever does become lady lane
都只是出于对Lane先生的爱慕 而不是惦记他的房
does so out of regard for Mr. Lane and not for his estate.
惦记车行吗?
What about his car?
快看呀 Lane先生骑马过来了呢
But look! Here approaches Mr. Lane himself,
跟着他妹妹的追求者 Moreno先生
along with his sister's admirer, Mr. Moreno.
早上好 Morgendorffer小姐 Quinn小姐
Good morning, Miss Morgendorffer, Miss Quinn.
祝福两位佳人今日愉悦
I pray the day finds you well.
也向两位祝好 先生们
And a good morning to you, sirs.
是啊 今早注定会是一个明媚的早晨
Indeed, it promises to be a glorious morning,
即使最坚硬的心也会为之融化
and one to gladden the stoniest of hearts.
诚愿如此 固然 世间荣华富贵皆为美
Let us hope so, indeed, for nothing so recommends this world
但最怡然仍是度过心旷神怡的每一天
as the promise with which it offers up each gentle day.
请问 在这晨露熹微的清早
And, pray, upon this dewy morning,
两位是有什么差事要远驾至此?
what errand is it that finds you guys abroad?
没有什么差事
Errand we have none.
不过非常幸运 我们今天外出运动
But with any luck, we shall have sport.
我们在等狩猎俱乐部的其他成员
We await the other members of our hunting party,
相信迎面过来的就是他们了
and I believe I glimpse them now.
早上好
Good day.
Quinn小姐 需要为你寻一处饮茶栖息处吗?
Miss Quinn, may I get you a bracing spot of tea?
需要防滑粉吗? 今天雾大容易手滑
Do you need a powder, to cure the vapors?
我来为你的钢琴调音吧
I'll tune your pianoforte.
Quinn呀 你的追求者好多 全都因为你是如此的完美动人
Oh, Quinn, your suitors are so numerous because you are so fair and good.
姐姐呀
Oh, sister,
凭你的智慧和判断力 一定可以嫁一个殷实又明智的郎君
your wit and judgment assure that you will marry not only well, but wisely.
她说"嫁"了吗?
Did she say "marry"?
是啊
Yeah.
就这样吧
Oh, well.
我写故事烂透了
I really suck at this.
不行 绝对不行
No. No, absolutely not.
没有商量的余地
That is unacceptable.
天啊 你爸这又是在煮什么呢?
Oh, my God, what has your father done now?
Jake
Jake!
Daria?
你哪里不舒服吗?
Is something wrong?
不舒服? 没呀
Wrong? Uh, no.
我在琢磨学校里老师留的一个作业呢
I'm thinking about an assignment I got in school.
妈能帮你点啥吗?
Anything I can help with?
算了
No.
我要写一个故事 把身边的人换成虚构角色写进去
I'm supposed to write a story using people I know as fictional characters.
是嘛 听起来棒极了
Really? That sounds fascinating.
别急啊 我写出来的东西就烂透了
Not so far. Everything I write comes out bad.
建立不起故事
I have no story.
我肯定...
Oh, I'm sure...
稍等一下 Daria
Hang on a second, Daria.
喂? 你那不叫买方还价 赤裸裸的侮辱好吧
Hellooo. No, that's not a counteroffer, it's an insult.
明天上班以后我会找你谈的
I will talk to you tomorrow during office hours.
再见
Good-bye!
好啦 说说其他孩子都写了什么咯
Okay, now, what are the other students writing?
他们不用写
They're not.
这是老师单独给我派的额外作业
This is an extra assignment just for me.
惩罚我如此聪明
A punishment for being smart.
好啦好啦 Daria
Now, come on, Daria,
妈妈相信只要你用心 一定可以写出好故事的
I'm sure you'll do a great job if you just put your mind to it.
你这话错到姥姥家了
You are very, very wrong.
一定可以的 你只管...
Sure you will. All you...
喂?! 明天 上班时间谈
Yes?! Tomorrow! During office hours.
你只管甩掉一身的酷细胞 放开手去写好了
All you have to do is get off your toches and do it!
人家Quinn一遇到挑战...
When Quinn has a challenge...
Quinn?
她遇到的挑战仅限于穿什么样的鞋子搭配男伴的眼睛颜色吧
All her challenges involve coordinating her shoes with the color of her date's eyes.
Daria 我要说的是...
Daria, what I mean is...
你干嘛要拿Quinn摆出来说事?
How can you talk to me about Quinn?
她才不会遇到这样的问题
She'll never have this kind of problem.
思考一类的问题
It involves thinking.
是你让我倾吐有什么烦恼 还一个劲儿接电话
You make me tell you what's wrong, in between calls,
结果就是拿Quinn举例?
and then you bring up Quinn?
你到底了不了解我啊?
Don't you know me at all?
有你的 Morgendorffer
Good one, Morgendorffer.
尼玛
Damn!
天啊 什么都不做就这么懒着简直爽死了
Man, what a good day to just kick back and chill.
说得一点不错
You got that right.
没空说话哟
Can't stop to talk.
四小时后去Stacy家参加盛大派对 该打扮咯
A big party at Stacy's in four hours. Gotta dress.
Quinn 你不觉得自己把社交这种事情看太重了吗?
Quinn, don't you think you've taken this popularity thing too far?
说你们一天到晚瞎玩
This well-liked teen crap.
就不能有点深度啥的吗?
Don't you have any depth at all?
怎么就不能跟Daira多学学?
Why can't you be more like Daria?
嘿 Daria
Oh, hey, Daria.
你们需要单独和Quinn谈一下吗?
Um, do you want to talk to Quinn alone?
不用 宝贝儿 其实呢
No, sweetie. As a matter of fact,
我们在跟她说 希望她能多跟你学学呢
we were just telling her how we wish she'd be more like you.
不止一次了
Again.
其实不是每个人都拥有...
Well, not everyone can have the same...
你们以为我不想像Daria一样嘛?
Don't you think I want to be more like Daria?
如果可以 我有怎么不想像她呢?
Don't you think I would if I could?
天啊 爸爸妈妈 你们怎么就搞不懂呢?
God, Mom and Dad, why won't you accept it?
我永远成不了Daria
I'll never be like Daria.
这是我的诅咒 也是我的负累
That's my curse... and my burden.
我知道这不怪你们
I know it's not your fault,
可看看你们又遗传了多少完美基因?
but look what your perfection has done to me.
我们不要去安慰一下她什么的吗?
Shouldn't we comfort her or something?
让她哭去吧
Oh, let her go.
会没事的
She'll get over it.
那至少也应该告诉她
We should at least tell her about
屋外的八道高速路晚上在施工吧?
that eight-lane highway they built outside the house during the night.
你这么说也对
Hmm... you may be right.
不是什么好事
That can't be good.
天呐
Ow! God!
又一大作
Another masterpiece.
如此看来 我这前半生都活在一场骗局里
So it turns out that my life up to now has been a sham.
我根本不会写东西 连简单的故事都编不出
I can't write. I can't produce a simple story.
哇 Daira 打死我也想不到你会缺少想象力呀
Wow, Daria. I never figured you for a lack of imagination.
我有想象力
I have imagination.
我可以想出各种点子 但没一个能让人感到真实
I can come up with all sorts of ideas, but none of them feels true.
那你对"真实"的定义是?
Well, what's your definition of "true"?
能讲出一些东西的东西
Something that says something.
怎么? 什么东西都行吗?
What? Anything?
不 意义 讲出意义的东西
No, something. About something.
我来整理下思路
Let me get this straight:
你是跟我说 你想写出点东西来
you're telling me you want to write something,
但不是什么东西都行 而是能讲出点东西的东西
not just anything, that says something about something.
没错
Right.
说你有沟通障碍 谁会信啊
Who'd ever believe you're having trouble communicating.
敲门的这位 我叫你什么?
Whom shall I say is calling?
Daria 你有什么事想要说出来的吗?
Daria, is there anything you want to talk about?
没 谢谢过问
No, thank you.
确定吗 亲爱的?
Are you sure, sweetie?
我需要自己静一静 让情绪平稳下来
I need some time alone to work out my feelings.
Daria
Daria!
或者玩填字游戏
Or do a crossword.
Daria...
Helen 我的炖菜 炉子着火了
Gah, Helen! My stew... the stove's on fire!
看在上帝份上...
Oh, for the love of...
邪恶之母 撒旦之妹 告诉我你在这污秽的炖菜中看到了什么?
Unholy mother, sister of Satan, tell me what you see in your filthy brew.
拨开时间的迷雾 说说我未来何在?
Say what the mists of time hold for me.
你付过款了吗?
Have you my payment?
我要新生儿的嫩嫩小肝脏
The tender liver of a newborn babe.
我... 来得有点急 你接受支票吗?
I, um, was in a rush. Will you take a check?
支票?! 你不会拿假身份证号哄我吧?
A check?! Have you two forms of I.D.?
告诉我你将赐予我力量
Tell me you can bring me power!
护佑我杀敌无数 凯旋而归
Power to crush my enemies, to triumph over all!
我可以赐予此等力量
Yes, I can bring you this power.
但凭什么好工作都得让男人拿下?
But why should men get all the good jobs?
告诉我你可以赐予我力量
Tell me you can bring me power!
护佑我杀敌无数 凯旋而归
Power to crush my enemies, to triumph over all!
真是等不及尝尝这炖菜了
I can't wait to taste this stew!
否则我以生养你的罪恶魔鬼之名发誓 我将统治这片大地
Or I swear by the unholy imp that spawned you, I will rule the land.
那我还统治什么啊?
But what do I get to rule?
闭嘴 没牙老巫婆
Silence, toothless hag!
干嘛对人家人身攻击
You don't have to get personal.
Daria 独家课业任务完成怎么样了?
Daria! How's the special assignment going?
我找您来就为这事儿
Um, that's what I want to talk to you about.
我不想做了
I'd like not to do it.
不要嘛 怎么了呢 Daria
Oh, no. What's the matter, Daria?
你什么也写不出来吗?
You haven't been able to write anything?
不是 我写了好多出来 可没有一个能拿得出手
No, I've written a lot of stuff, but it's not up to my standards.
而且我有点烦 因为我也不知道什么叫拿得出手
And that disturbs me, because I don't have standards.
怎么呢?
What's wrong?
都是因为要拿身边的人做角色来源
It's this idea of using people I know as characters.
我觉得还是完全虚构出来一拨人比较好办
I think I might be better off with a bunch of characters I just made up.
可这正是科幻小说挑战人的地方呀 Daria
But that's the challenge of the fiction writer, Daria.
将现实生活中的所见所感融会贯通 再注入到非现实之中
To take what we learn in real life and turn it into something that's not really real,
其自身又构成了某种意义上的现实
but has a real life all its own.
好吧 理论上听起来很赞 应该是吧
Well, that sounds great in theory... I think.
不过我想不出我的那些角色应该做些什么
But I can't figure out what my characters should be doing.
没事 这很好办
Okay. That's not a problem.
我们微调一下作业的要求
We'll alter the assignment slightly.
有些时候界限反而能给我们带来自由
Sometimes boundaries can paradoxically provide us with freedom.
我们就来写一写活动相关的东西吧
We'll say it should include an activity of some kind.
想想哈 森林篝火吗?
Let's see... a forest fire?
不行 那可能就成了悲剧了
No, that could end in tragedy.
要不写写去检查视力?
Some kind of orthoscopic surgery?
不行 那太凌乱了
No, that can get messy.
有了 写纸牌游戏
I know, a game of cards!
纸牌游戏?
A game of cards?
对啊 随便写什么样的纸牌游戏都可以
Sure, and it can be any card game you want!
天 谢了 真是太有帮助了
Gee, thanks. That'll really help.
很高兴你这么说 加油
Glad to hear it. Have fun.
罪恶之母 撒旦之妹 告诉我你在这污秽的炖菜中看到了什么?
Unholy mother, sister of Satan, tell me what you see in your filthy brew.
拨开时间的迷雾 说说我未来何在?
Tell me what the mists of time hold for me.
你付过款了吗? 我要新生儿的嫩嫩小肝脏
Have you my payment? The tender liver of a newborn babe?
我肝脏有点缺货
I'm a little short on livers.
这样吧 跟你玩一个五张抽牌小魔术怎么样?
Tell you what: play you a quick game of five-card stud for it.
选J没得跑
Jacks are wild.
Daria? Daria 电视没开
Daria? Daria, the TV's not on.
嘘 我在看呢
Shh! I'm watching this.
Daria 妈妈很抱歉之前没有太照顾你的感受
Daria, I'm sorry about not being more sensitive earlier.
确定没因为拿两个闺女互相比较...
Doesn't comparing one sibling to another
在教子入门课上得不及格嘛?
get you an automatic "F" in Parenting 101?
世上没有教子入门课
There is no Parenting 101.
这也是问题所在
That's the problem.
没有哪门课能教会你怎么做一个完美的家长
There's no course that can teach you to be a perfect mother.
显而易见
That's obvious.
Daria 妈妈为之前没能帮到你道歉
Daria, I apologized for not helping you before.
我现在来帮助你了
I'm offering to help you now.
你现在要做什么?
What do you want to do?
我的故事烂透了
My story sucks.
亲爱的 我相信只要再多给你一天或者两天...
Well, honey, I'm sure if you just give it another day or two...
我能做的都已经做了
Everything I do has already been done.
我想写点有意义的东西出来
I wanted to write something meaningful.
可我什么也写不出来
I can't write anything at all.
也许你有点过度在意了
Maybe you're trying too hard.
没必要写出什么有意义的东西 只要写出真实的东西就好了
Maybe you don't have to write something meaningful, just something honest.
真实的东西我可以
I can do honest.
看看周围 描述我看到的东西就好了
I look around me, I describe what I see.
不如写点你想要看到的场景咯 如实来写
How about describing what you'd like to see, honestly?
这话什么意思?
What do you mean?
Daria 世上最简单的事莫过于...
Daria, the easiest thing in the world for you
如实看待眼前的一切
is being honest about what you observe.
所以...
And...
难的在于 如实面对内心里的渴望
What's hard for you is being honest about your wishes.
你觉得事情该是什么样子 如果不该是现在这样的话
About the way you think things should be, not the way they are.
你用愤世嫉俗的吐槽遮掩着内心的渴望
You gloss over it with a cynical joke
没人知道你真正信仰什么
and nobody finds out what you really believe in.
看来我的邪恶计划奏效了
So my evil plan is working.
如果你想要真实的东西 就要诚心说出自己希望事情什么样
If you really want to be honest, be truthful about what you'd like to happen.
这可是挑战所在
There's a challenge.
你什么时候这么了解我的?
When the hell did you learn so much about me?
这事很有趣的 Daria
It's a funny thing, Daria.
对于给予了她生命的人 你会不自觉想密切监视她
You give birth to someone, you just get an urge to keep tabs on them.
嗨 亲爱的
Oh, hi, sweetie.
还好吗 老妈?
How are you, Mom?
很不错 就是每天早晨从床上爬起来要稍微费一点劲
Pretty good. You know, every morning it's a little harder to get out of bed.
我也是
For me, too.
你老爸就不一样了 好像一天比一天年轻似的
Your father, on the other hand, seems to be getting younger every day.
自从退休 他这人生才算是开启了新篇章
Ever since he retired he's developed such a wonderful perspective.
男人做过心脏搭桥手术是会这样的
Well, triple bypass surgery will do that for a man.
Marcello怎么样了?
How's Marcello?
还在和其他教工奋争课程表上的课时呢
Oh, fighting the same old curriculum battles against the rest of the faculty.
帮助宝宝学会控制大小便的训练
另外每年秋天都是新生的如厕训练季
And each fall there's a new batch of freshmen to potty-train.
你这种的专栏写的不错
I enjoyed your column this week.
我们本打算和脱教者布道
We're preaching to the converted.
我义愤填膺 读者也义愤填膺 结果就是没有结果
I get outraged, the readers get outraged, and nothing happens.
有时我都觉得自己应该转战电视台
Sometimes I think I should have gone into television.
你上电视 Daria?
You in television, Daria?
是啊 我还是别扯了
I know. Who am I kidding?
你们俩有没有好好谈谈要小孩的事情啊?
Has there been any further discussion about expanding your little family?
妈... 你知道我还没准备好要宝宝
Mom... you know I'm not ready for kids.
一想到要小孩我就很不安 也不知道是为什么
The whole idea makes me uneasy and I'm not sure why.
给我
Give me that!
不给 我的
No, it's mine!
妈咪
Mommy!
想起来了 所以我不想要小孩
Oh, yeah. Now I remember.
嗨 你们知道奶奶家的电视在哪
Hi. You know where Grandma's TV is.
去找乖节目看去吧
Go watch something educational.
天呐 累死我了
Boy, I'm exhausted.
面向少女的隆胸手术...
Breast implants for chickens...
这个不行
Not that!
还好吗 Quinn?
How are you, Quinn?
您知道的 日复一日 孩子复孩子
Oh, you know, another day, another baby.
我发誓 趁哪天Jamie不注意
I swear, one of these days I'm going to slip something into Jamie's beer
我非得往他酒里放点什么 然后出去做结扎手术
and while he's unconscious, I'm going to go out and get my tubes tied.
更高明的是让他做
Better yet, his tubes.
老爸怎么样? 叫我们来有事?
How's Dad? And what's he want?
我挺好 咕咕
I'm great. Goo-goo.
抱歉 那啥 姑娘们 爸想修改一下遗嘱...
Sorry. You know, girls, I was going over my will...
又来啊
Not again.
老爸 您干嘛这么心重啊?
Daddy, why are you so morbid?
这话我也问过他
That's exactly what I asked him.
可我就是想改一下遗嘱
But I like going over my will.
满满都是钞票呀
It's got all that money!
老爸 两周前你才刚刚修改过
Dad, you revised your will two weeks ago
因为你在阁楼上发现你以前的废纸编织环了
when you discovered your old gum wrapper chain in the attic.
孩子们肯定会喜欢的
The kids are going to love that.
好了 大伙来谈谈我改遗嘱的事儿吧
Anyway, who said anything about revising my will?
那 这次又要怎么改?
So, what are we doing here?
我读了自己的遗嘱 回顾过去 遥想未来
Well, I was reading my will, thinking about the past and the future,
忽然就想到 你们俩姑娘都变成了爸爸希望的样子
and it occurred to me that you girls have turned out exactly the way I hoped.
好了啦
Come on.
Daria 每周你都会有自己的专栏
Daria, every week you write that column of yours,
努力唤醒人们接近真相
trying to wake people up to the truth.
我闺女可是个改革者
My daughter, the crusader.
好吧 说着同样的话 高中时被看成异己...
Well, there is some pleasure in winning awards
现在却凭它拿了大奖 感觉也还不错
for saying the same things that made me an outcast in high school.
再说Quinn...
And Quinn,
你把过去一个劲儿要变得... 稍微有那么点自以为是的劲头
you've taken all that energy and enthusiasm you used to direct toward being,
把那股劲头和热情...
um, a teensy bit self-absorbed...
老爸 我那时是不知天高地厚的小恶魔
Oh, daddy, I was a stuck-up little nightmare.
全都倾注到养育孩子们身上了
...and put it all into bringing up those kids.
这可不是轻松活儿 相信妈 妈懂的
And that's no easy task. Believe me, I know.
怎么从来没听你抱怨过你们家这几个小淘气鬼 Quinn?
How come you never complain about those little monsters of yours, Quinn?
我爱他们呀 爸
Um, I like them, Daddy.
我还是搞不懂今天到底要干嘛
I'm still not clear on what all this is about.
老爸想起了许多过去的事情 然后我就想 嘿
Well, I was having so much fun reminiscing I thought, hey!
咱干嘛不像过去一样 一家人一起玩玩家庭卡片游戏?
Why don't we get together for a family card game just like we used to?
家庭卡片游戏?
Family card game?
我们就从来都没玩过家庭卡片游戏的好不?
We never played a family card game in our lives.
Daria说的对
Daria's right.
我又听到了
Oh, do I hear that.
我记得叫我爸爸一起去"钓鱼"
I remember asking my father to play "go fish"...!
小心搭桥啊 爸
Triple bypass, Dad!
好 我没事
Okay, I'm all right.
那好吧 去他的 我们压根就没玩过家庭卡片游戏
Anyway, so screw it, then, we never played a family card game.
那我们现在玩咯
Let's play one now!
- 桥? - 松子酒
- Bridge? - Gin.
- 桃心 - 好嘞
- Hearts. - Done.
成啦 我要玩桃心游戏
Okay. I'm going to play a game of hearts
跟我漂亮的老伴儿和两个棒棒的闺女
with my beautiful wife and my two great kids.
Jake
Oh, Jake.
怎么样 Daria? 选桃心?
How about it, Daria? Hearts?
算我咯
Deal me in.
不太好 对吧?
It's not very good, is it?
Daria...
Oh, Daria...
也没那么糟吧
It wasn't that bad.
干嘛 干嘛 故事而已 不是真的
Stop, stop! This isn't a story, it's real life!
你写的故事把你妈给看哭了?
Wow, so your story made your mother cry?
喜极而泣 这是烦人的地方
Out of happiness. That's the sick part.
再说说她为啥哭来着?
And run the reason by me again.
她觉得这事儿说明 我私底下其实没有看上去的那么隔路
She took it as evidence that I'm secretly not as alienated as I seem or something.
得花好多年才能消除这误解了
It'll take me years to undo the damage.
要拿给O'Neill老师看嘛?
So you going to show it to O'Neill?
别无选择
I have no choice.
但要是他也哭 我就打算退学了
But if he cries, too, I'm dropping out of school.
听着 反正你现在态度也端正了 啥都挺好
Well, listen, now that you've got such a great attitude and everything,
能把靴子送我吗?
can I have your boots?
行啊 转过去 我现在就送你一脚
Yeah. Turn around and I'll give you one right now.
Daria 你看... 哪天...
Daria, do you think... someday...
我能读读你的故事吗?
I can read your story?
不行 不过你可以读读你和Kevin私奔的那个
No. But you can read the one where you run away with Kevin.
啥?!
What?!
欢迎微博关注
@漫迪字幕组